know-how
so
was used in it
geography relevant here talk to them
there there's chicken-and-egg problem to
know more
the last one
these newly market dot and you could
write down everything it's
sir
uh...
now
it's one of the things work out
instructions that you can't have an air
check some filed because you have it on
them
if you keep your father directions
exactly
you'll end up with a slightly different
file
of a percent
e
this verdict used to it
themselves okay
lecture eats
part today
hammer have you guys were totally from
the virtual machine
it was causing the problem switching
back and forth between the mac and
virtual machine
i'm going to submit virtual machine
initiative
otherwise
joking
so we talk a little bit about the
homework
before they kill went farther
in his first homework
i'm going to be
lenient on some things if you made some
mistakes it's their first time digging
into you
he max and working with some of the
stuff
if you get to the and
there's one slight problem i believe
so if you're down here working on
build your submission
so there's a to-do item in your bill the
submission
and if you're building your submission
and then you
do the check some of it and then you
market to do in the file you working on
it's not going to be there and answer
if you mark that
expect to see that to do
marked as done yet
when you create your car
because you're working on the stuff
you've saved your
work probably working on any of export
it
and then when you're done with entry
that i would expect you to go back and
flag dot
but at that point you've already
put onto a car
and checked some of it
if you market dime
while i'll never see that so
it's okay if that's not marked its done
if you have a former gathered that
doesn't matter
bucket what does matter is character
here and try to
pay very close attention to detail
with command line
is a little less forgiving if you've on
one side of the button verse the eyes of
the button in the killing
it'll probably working both ways
but here if u
have typos or not phones russians
exactly
he'll do things that
part whites expecting finite
for example if you send me
meet our file in the email or email
server might tell you to take a hike in
the things that's a virus that it's got
a script in there and
no bounces
or it might give you all kinds of crazy
virus warns when i was asking for was
just to check some so we are submitting
it
just haven't checked some
i don't respond to you in a return email
that means either what you sent me
didn't make sense
i didn't get it back to got beaten by s
pam filter i think there's at least one
homework
happened to it
where r
email filter
sucked into the great nothing
destroy the homework hey you know
suggest send a check some
just like number
and the file name as mt five some puts
out out
and that will make it through ur email
filtering no problem panel to look at
the server homework
but just remember potentially huge oil
is super important at this stuff
right now you probably having a hard
time knowing what's detail it matters
and what doesn't it just try to be
careful about everything and you start
seeing plan
if you press an extra space in something
you might be okay
right now it's gonna be hard for you to
cast that
so just try to follow exactly what's
going on
i'll start again
a little bit better sense of that
so let's jump in tuesday's
what i'm going to do is an accident
download
beadwork file i started putting
the or file so heres
lecture eight
september twenty-second
there the html files here and or file
if i click on it
there will be new york files on a backup
on the right click on it save link as
and the save this lecture eight
frame i hope directory
and i'm gonna put away
firefox for now
want to do is i mean it going to
what i want to fight back there behind
that
but before i do that i am almost
forgotten to do something that i had
anything for this class and trying to
you
i'm not too many to open up a terminal
don't fall off is because you don't have
it applications accessories
i wrote a script for today
it is gonna grab of my screen
every few seconds and save it to an
image
and then i can go back through and find
the critical images and make a little
pbf or something that will have to keep
pictures from today so you don't just
have to hear it can read about you can
actually see a few pictures
i think a specially with the max
having screenshots of what actually
happens is going to be helpful
and the video gets pretty
something more about terminal for the
rest of clients
and i'm gonna go and open up imax
and shootings jeffrey dahmer this work
file
in the email acts
i'm going to split the window into you
and i'm and i have
the or growth file on one side
animal open up a shell on the other side
then reminded me that's
you can actually use a terminal cell
within sight of you max
and not
will reinforce
the shelling the max like to play
together
and what do you see
hotkeys in
u_-mass they often work
in the back shell to you
when we do things like cotton pace with
the keyboard
it's not good for the other key addition
to control see things like that
the via special entry maxell actually
work
in the shell
to make this
and we're trying to break the commands
up here
but if i do something and i forget to
write appearing to getting confucius let
me know
the first one
where open up a directory
so if you go profiles from
the menu words before the menus
unfortunately
might fingers no the comedians
but not my brain
c x
c_f_ of file
for the nice part you can do with the
max
is the period
as somebody point up or stopped
so see if i can do that control acts
control acts controller
and will say fine file down at the
bottom there and does he in a vacuum
after
first and ask to see some of us
remember that till days your home
directory
so if we just put a period on their says
that it ending up being
till the slash was already there for me
and i put a period
and hit enter and you're not gonna see
ur home directory
the forces that all of your dot files to
use it for crack cocaine
and i'm going to go find
lecture aids which i believe is in
decided a control x
control half
and then
if you start pressing tab
it wants to help you complete just like
the sheldon
going toward download cyprus a deed
a capital p_ and you'll start seeing
uh... d related
things said downloads
and there's nothing prohibits it
i'm gonna show you research command the
collective using this all throughout the
day and i'll never forget if i don't
know
any max there is aid very powerful
search and then there's the normal
search
and lazy i used the normal search
hopefully by the innocent of strategy
guides the super powerful search and
you'll be doing really amazing stuff
controlled
in the latter ass that's a lower case
that's so that's a
control s
and then you start writing
and that's gonna do a search for you
so could you
control bats you'll now see at the
bottom
he says i've search
and there's other kinds of searches but
this is the simple one
we're just gonna start typing
so all type of how about uh... dropped
diario p
for dropbox
and you'll see there's a bunch of stuff
related dropbox there is highlighting
one of them
and if you press this
control that's
again the second time it's gonna jump to
the next one
salty of control lots
or on the next dropbox
control s
and me on this next dropbox
and i use the bottom
added one more time
failings search because i'm at the end
the file
see you open up the dot
so perfect
she read the full stop
yet the press that
and then make this
click on this is made up for spring
under the that jewelsburg button
so now it's full screen
clicking that'll hold many women
impressive carrion
now press answer
they remembered
currently stuck in
split mode for you got to different
screens
that was control
times what
lost on
and if you need to be able to cure the
wrong window
we're getting a lot of little
perks in the beginning as you guys to
use this if you're in the wrong window
anybody on here but you're actually
somewhere else
as trying to work down here you can just
click
down that bottom section
wave your hand if you're stuck
we will get all of it
awesome everybody's stuff perfect
for service plan to go ahead making max
beautiful spring so everybody if you
have a happy masking fullscreen
just forget about me elsewhere now
startup imax
click about square box
the right handed
okay sir go ahead and open up that
directory so control acts
control f
and then
a_k_ post-op press enter
yet they go scenario in the directory
edit mode
and now you can give control at stance
toward trying to search
and try drop
d_r_
because he hasn't i could start a catch
more more stuff
energy control that's again
and if you want to get out of that
control g is the quick ki
and they keep saying these until you
guys are sick of hearing me say them
takes a while
he told you yet
you'd where with
uh...
yet so you are scroll down only see how
your school boards down here a you
scroll up
finances but some of the problem
law context yet so now you're going to
start seeing it matches you can't relax
and then drop
and control us again
excellence
amit it's gonna fail so students or
fails
and if you get one more time you go back
to the top file
etc
you have to go destruction of autumn
he'll fail
prescott ross again that jumps is hot
so you've actually search for capital
drop
assessing just lower case
right now it's plain if you type any
capital letters in your search it
becomes case-sensitive
if you take all lower case it'll match
either upper and lower case
direct control team
g vigilant
and to control afs and then dropped d_r_
o_ p_
net don't click anywhere
were you yet put down here
tecra
that don't presenter
because enter then
uh... and here to search
so put back in here
now control s
so applications
accessories
lead
the first look at the museum act that
seems insane and then eventually you see
it
starts
since
right
yes equipped engineer this is called the
many buffer of the bombs at the pleasure
drop yep
now press control ass
and see how it's just a little local
borealis
alms if you do more time to come back as
a reception from the top
i had no plan yet
were just playing with search uh...
and remember
if there's like two split window thing
you want to the bottom one control x and
then just a wonderful make that go
so i'm looking for a lecture eight is
what i was looking for
before we start doing search
and so
if i do control that's and i was in
seeing it because it was not where i
thought it would be
eight dash
is on finding it attack control that's
second time
if out of the top
and then
when your cursor somewhere on this file
just press the enter a return key
and you're now looking at
today's lecture notes so i'm going to be
copying and pasting from lecture notes
into a terminal
on side of the matter
if this doesn't confuse you guys that
i'm not kidding not free
uh... if you put together a
usko profiles
installed for prop opt card connected to
my hometown weaknesses we are not your
own dropouts pervert
and and for this case
dropbox we may use it if you want to
file someplace later on and get stuck
but
did download from firefox so if you
don't have this file
girl into
firefox here and right click
people work file
research tools page
troubles over here
what's going on
now control g_m_
yet to looking for that
we'll give her the eight
yet with him
controlled used to quit
haha
you can if you want
if you're comfortable putting in your
drop box and going there
that's great i'm miss going into my home
directory for today
down the road
it's up to you how to organize things on
t_v_ suggestions to the fact that if you
wanted a place
doesn't really matter
when you get into the into me
on the server
vocational matter so i can find it
but other than that its
if you can't find it
yes
did you download the
feel of a file from
we're really having fun
just to warn you huh
email x's quite capable of opening up
archives like this it's and dot deb
files and you can end up
looking inside of some compressed thingy
and and in the future
so i opened up your home directory under
the control acts control efforts period
and an answer
here
that's the strategy download the
or the file
in firefox circuits in the possible page
so backup
and right click on the org
and save
you can also if you don't want to do
exactly max you can go back and forth
from
firefox but it's best if you just use
this had to sit in your home directory
to success
is everybody able to save uh... followed
their home directory it speaks dash so
it's that live here they could you
control s
eight-second then batch
unsealed says failing
press control us and you go back up to
the top and find it
okay now just pressed enter
and open the file
professor again
quick
yes
right
now if you haven't downloaded when
you're in the directory of load
the letter
she will refresh your perfect revealed
you want to say that file into home
directory
press enter to finish your search
and press enter again to open the file
awesome you just open up a binary file
now
give actual happily do that it's okay
control access zero closes the window
here in
and then destroy number zero
open up your home directory again
so control acts
control of
period enter okay now
scroll way at pressing g
to reload your directory
and see others anita patel eight dash
more
you can either click on mac for
with the mouse up there with the air
appeasement person to outline
anybody know i have this file up yet
you are in research tools
or anything
'cause you're sitting here resurgent no
nahe
oughtn't have opened up
and debbie in file or some related stuff
so
goats click on the buffers main european
out of control
acts controller
corporate directory of press enter
to refresh that you can
the letter g_
and now you see how you have this p m
dash more appeared at the top
and you are now looking at the file
all right
yeah you miss one thing though it's all
so the next thing resume as we want to
be able to split this into you
so that we can see the class notes and
one
and we can work in the other
if you press control acts
and then the number two
it's gonna split
and if you want to see that menu
that's right here with
split window control act soon and too
so these two
the unspoiled and the split are related
so we now have to be using the same file
was a little strange
we can screw around
and work in one
and the other one doesn't change
so for really long document that's kinda
cool movie and then you can work on
something you can see on the part
is also can be a little strange
for example i start typing in one
appears in the other which can be
a little too starving
but what we're gonna do is we're going
to start a shell in one of them
and i would put up top because it then
we can see better out there
any max
so we have the control of the season is
another one
this m
means matter
and there's two ways to do this one and
foresee this was the confusing one
there used to be a medic he on the
keyboard and probably willing to listen
here have seen keyboards with the mana
kiya on them
i believe that's
on the dealt seaboard
so if you pull down
seared right
you've done a lot of stuff ok excellent
so what you can do if you want to close
at so great now hearing human if we
don't want to have
you can't you can't relax and then a
zero
you're cooking on too many things that
the mouse soap
the vanass alone there for a second
ticking off the mouse
this is the key word stick to the
keyboard
control x
and that is zero
the number zero
so that when a weight control x
and zero
now underway
so now you can do this split which is
control x two and also of the body else
about the controllers a second
control act nineteen
and now the number two
yeah definitely
three will split this way
there's a bunch of other ones they all
have with happens there's hundreds of
mappings
manned
would be
because you if you scroll around it will
change things a little bit it's okay to
be were ever in each of them
that there's nothing wrong with that
it that's ok
so if you want to
get rid of the window the urine there's
control
zero with the number zero
get rid of
or hide
the hudson river
yes and
control
acts
and uh... i might have
for troubles on the board
this is the letter over hasn't offset it
and that says go to the other window
so if you're in one went up to the other
you'll see them in our made to a lot of
this woman to go to from one of the
other
all with the keyboard in the contents
the mouse
so controllers other
halen height you can discuss menu and
select that offer ammo will do a lot of
opportune time later on
i think it's a choice d switched to
buffer
and then they depressed how tonight
you'll get a list of offers that you
have available
we're going to go through this all lot
throughout the semester
expect you guys not to get health today
but there
if you want to get rid of
decline
uso
use control accident coz jump to the
next one but but ma swe
so
control extol and then the lateral
without the control of the up and that
moved you from this was this one you do
it one more time to talk before the top
anybody but you will need to be able to
if he's going to so good to us
dreadful
near the top wants us to work that was
control accident numbers
to control x
number zero
and if you can also drive that little
bar up adult benefits
dot where you want to see it
mostly guys dot
this one i don't know the keyboard
shortcuts house
season dragons bar up and down
and control with wire
as you get stuck
just wave your hands
all right
keep waving your hands until you get
comfortable
so you've got this first about for going
on below
seated
your control acts
and then i'll
to jump to any other window
which happens in the buffer
the quickie is controlled g
all right you guys are actually getting
it allot faster than
well dl
back-to-work workout
the altar he hopefully on
this it is
is probably the medicaid so hold down
default g
the letter acts once
and you're gonna see
of little howell
dash acts of here
and i do a bad thing
i'm tempted
type toward tetris
and press enter
and you know are facing tetris
if you if i get you playing times it's
not just during class i'll be very
disappointed
at my own fault
theory have tetris out because
depressed alts
and then acts
gelato
anti-tax rest
displays all right
we now have the most serious five cents
each call
dahlia
controls you
rejections to sort of rehab to now do
you let us
content-type tetris
the center
all right we're testers we have
everybody almost playing factors
separate out here
okay
a ticket sorry
dosages do you are where you are which
is fine just you know that's some
recalls
and press acts
and insight tetris
press enter
the keeping thorugh now is
how to get rid of tetris
control acts
the letter k
so i'm a search efforts fear
and i'm in a killer
somatic acts
tetris
so not sure tetris
retype the letter
birth control acts
s_e_c_ fisher asi acts of the bottom
impress the letter k without a control
it's gonna say kill buffer
it's going to fall to the most recent
buffer that you've used or you can't
abigail see a list
but we want the default suggested
and tetris should be after st
to control its one
intelligent pool
potentially
but the analogy would control acts
letter k
filter access course that's okay
it set up to have a score file
and the permissions are funny on the
score file so it can save your high
school
so i'm sorry we can't keep a record
your high school
uh... so yeah you can get control x k in
that one if you want
there's a couple different ways to do it
supplement
kill a buffer
so if i do you control x can win the
direct not top
it defaults the one i pressed out don't
give me a list
so that i can start going to them
and i believe you can actually clip at
the mouth if you wanted to you
if unit at its gonna wait and if i try
and hit like eight
and tab
you know then
fill that out
and remember control if you want to go
and get control to you
undo the last thing you did
if you look at it
their is
undi does not have the key listed
its control
and then
you have to hold on the ship he admits
the underscore
i believe sometimes it's not too meadows
easier
windows in your
but i'm not sure that seems to be
but if you're in good people undo window
changes so it only and does everything
inside windows
so we'll be looking to undo history act
so
do control act zero and that's what will
go away
and making a good choice to displays
so let's go ahead and start the shell
which is where we were trying to go to a
awhile back
uh... you know what i had too much fun
with the maxim if you do this
given that acts thing that we just did
and despite
pentax shell
will get you
a nice little terminal
nak seriously they um...
dash acts all type of the word shell
and press enter
and i'm now in
the show much like a bus terminal is
going to work
a little bit differently here in there
but it's going to work a lot easier with
he max ones here
used e max the first
expected for the next three or four
lectures
lesser four lectures imax is gonna feel
wierd
and by the end the semester
so i ask you what the key stroke was and
you won't know but your fingers now it's
kind of strange
pause and if you ask me something
i have to walk over to a keyboard and do
it
it's fair and if you get stock you can
deal most all the stuff
from the menus
so there is lots of options appear
things with you
next time coming to get you guys logging
inorg modem
so that
for the rest of the semester you'll be
taking notes inside at work
every class
and i have you can write whatever you
want but then if you entry for every
class after this one
we'll give you one more classes for the
east thirty max for four you have to
start
logging stuff in it
come tuesday i want you guys to have a
log file open
be able to create entry for the day and
then put at least one little thing in it
for each class so we have thereafter
will skip that for now
let's go work with
so you guys having done to make any
plots yet and i apologize and today's
weren't trying correct that's fast if we
can we're gonna go
lots of data
remember if you're in the other window
you know what you can't relax old
horribly zines amounts
and the very first thing that we're
going to
is in this begin source
we're going to make a directory tree
and remember the dash he creates
multiple directories if it needs to
so you can even type dot
or you can copy it but
will type it
so recreate a record called class
will have each class under their has a
number
we're going to class
and you can still do all the normal
stuff that you would do with the
terminal
later on if you want we can actually
open up this directory three directory
edit mode at the same time and we can
get herself with a computer
but this is world work today
i've gotten frustrated with this command
called
that you get
so we're gonna switch today
a music man called
or seaview r_l_
it's another tool that goes on so wet
and that's why it's
you know it's not installed
i would suggest opening up a terminal
sold to you
applications accessories
terminal because vmware is hiding on
dice quickstart
sudo
dash yet
space
install
c you are out
press enter
your password here
so you can use the this password right
here
and if he does for me
it's a tough
you know it's hard installed don't worry
that for you you should see
a yes or no question that we want small
bunch of stuff
and it should take all of about
ten seconds to install
so why and then enter
or yes
back to gain access so we now have curl
let's go get the data off
the server
scandia edit copy
scenario type of research tools aspirin
so the exclamation point
our team
their difference written by different
people
and they have never
come to an agreement about how it should
be done
so they're all
slightly different
if u really won't know i will point to
ferment tickets and
yes union curled meant that you get and
then try to figure out
why one is better than ever if you come
up with the conclusion
i'd love to hear it
are kinda cool and i both
something ours
yet dissident great
installing
by the end of this class you'll all be
professional sustenance traitor defect
but
so click in that window where you fell
asleep stuff
can you control acts and not the latter
how
hasn't offset
so now do you can't relax
purcell and repeat
christopher's
tab
let's give you a list concedes that
eight dash more there to tap water eight
now enter
the next
there you go do israel and paste
so if you saw highlighted that stuffing
the bird on baseball in your head
toothpaste commands
is actually called
this is bowl terminology that came about
before
microsoft windows and
before he ever forgive yourself yes
footsteps point
so yank
was what they call that way back when in
the nineteen seventies so that's their
cohen a paste
so if i just typed control why in here
all pays back him and then or you could
look at a pace
which of course it doesn't have the
alias in there
pressed enter
and he should then have downloaded to
your data
if you violate a region
so if you want to start marking a region
its control
fits right here
is the space for
cigarettes the space bar that marks the
beginning of where you're selecting
you can then move around at the arrow
keys full wesley all teach you all of
the keyboard motion stuff
then when you get to the end
there's two things there's a
and control w
met at W packages
and this is cut
control
we actually do this year
and so if we do you control space
remark in the in the line
now fight your control w
the lines drawn
but now i can press control why bring it
back
i do
a bunch tonight
to amanda
which fantasy escape you can also be
escape heat by itself
and it's a little bit different
got a copy it
the crazy thing about this
is that it saves every single thing that
you have
copied or cut
since the start the program
in a giant brings officers tons of these
around
you actually
can go back to something that you copied
like fifteen minutes ago
and find in there
deal then evil the pace all kinds of
crazy stuff but if you can keep track of
that stuff
awesome high i can't
i can remember the last one or two maybe
so i don't try to
remember all those but if you say
something allow back we want to get it
back it's in here
you know select my train leaving the
keyboard he's mastered
so now you've got back
and
this prolonged the absolute more we need
to uncompressed discuss again we saw
this is a busy to file
retype file
starring here you'll see that we have
one the zipped you compressed
so the command was beyond zip
tab completion work sophie type
do you and then pressed habit all
complete up to feelings it to you
are filing so holes thought csd dot easy
too
so it got ourselves some data
we can start running some of these
commands you'll get used to if you get
datafile you know what it was in their
come look at it to the story is about to
do that so workouts
dash ulf remember of lines
holes
so we have three thousand forty-seven
lines in this file
let's take a look at that will run the
had command on it
and holes caught csd
what we have a year
is a data base that i got from i'd
believe university of texas from the
database manager
that list
everywhere
the international drilling programs have
put the four holes into
three thousand forty seven holes in this
database where scientists are going out
into role a successful for lucy for
all over the globe
and it still working
that's a little wierd
uh... prison term
mon-fri put button to see what's going
on
killer
concert
writes a good open up another shell
circular
but you can't put down here in germany
xcel
to mount it on that acts
alternates
an intent show
now cv
but what you're here
so now you can to dallas
that show
seaweed
okay you have a looks good nasa tried at
work and again today bc
space
dash l
phase
holes dot csd
sometimes it
click click here and stuff you end up in
a motive and i was sure which love
itself before we start back over it
i'm not sure that that take a look at
our buffers
who sees the committee here
ceo sigit before when i was shell select
that one
cooking it quickly because when they
appear to dig in and select like he's
graphical user interface skewing
do you want
youi kiwi
parts and now we've got the word count
what we've got in here
is the way comma-separated values files
tend to work if you're lucky
is that hopefully the first wind list
out the columns that you want
out what times
that won't be the case in your packet
gas
and that's no fun
but here
the first columns of these ones here as
expedition
this text over here has been the site
then this is the whole within that site
so we have some naming scheme for how
they have these things
program
here this is the s_d_p_ deep-sea
drilling program there's also pushing
billing program
will see those in a minute
here's your your love to be allowed to
go to the part that we cared most about
as we can plot come out
the water depth
in meters
and how much corps they got back out of
the c_ four
so let's go and see if we can
do something with this data
because i think this is pretty exciting
stuff
so we're going to use the cut commands
to try and learn a little bit more about
this scenario used to cut commands
and before we those before so
we can use the dash d
for characters say what art one letter
is
and we can cut into different fields
if you are a lot more of the country and
i would recommend going read that man
page
it's uh...
boring but useful
and we can say we want to cut
a particular field so in this case
if we look up here we have expedition is
field number one site is still number
two
is still number three
and the fourth one is program so let's
see if we could find out what programs
are in this file
if we do you
in the same holes thought csd
and despite that the head
receiving a whole bunch of
d_s_ gps
the first one the program
anything about units is we can start
combining things together
so if i teach you another
command called unique
we do
and anything about this is i think this
will work if you could just grow up to
an old command and you could have a bit
so what i've done as i've gone up
about to hold him and i had
i've changed it to be something
different for for for a head
head here
and he said that to be unique
u_n_
i_q_ and what that will do
is it takes the inputs hewitt edit find
all the winds are duplicates in collapse
on down to just the unique entries
so this is unyk command to use if you
have a whole bunch of data and so forth
repetitive
so here we have over three thousand
lines of entries
there any kind and we found out there's
three programs in here
so there's that
deep-sea drilling program d s_d_p_
the which came next is the lucien
drilling program
and finally came the international
motion drilling program i'll be p
and what we can do that as we can slices
apart based on islamic applaud on each
one of those
or to figure out how many are in each
one of these
believe in the reading room right behind
bans bacteria
next to that is a library
and in there we have some of these
volumes from these joint programs
satisfying the site this particularly
interesting you can go read all about it
bullets go take another look at
uh... what we have here so we can do
is we can use a command called
peremptories before
search for all the entries with the
s_d_p_
to file for starts e_s_p_
and we can do a workout on back
so we've taken the output
from we've taken the whole thought csd
file the grep command searches for a
pattern to any line that contains
the four letters in a row d s_d_p_
it's the return only does this also u
reruns
for one thing is there's and weird
quirks when you weren't had sometimes
things get pretty
resort or anything that matches the
s_d_p_
which was pretty boring
you know we can then go into the same
thing review he grabbed
odp
holes dot csc
vertical bar for the fight
workout so
we came up with nineteen
hundred and thirty
the odp
hi l_d_p_
falls
dot csc
ocap
now there's something a little
wrong going on here
so we've got
three thousand forty seven
lines
the first one of those is a program line
but then we've got
one thousand one hundred sixteen for one
one thousand nine hundred and thirty for
the next
one hundred fifty three for the economy
and that was like it's more of an
the number of lines that
we expected to have at three thousand
point seven
why might there be more lines
in those three grep commands
then what we saw
in the actual for workout
list for the whole file
why are we seeing more injuries than we
expected to have that
fought as the one that might be
exactly you're picking up the odp in the
eye of the p
so we search for cody p
it's also picking up the i_r_t_ p
because
inside the word coyote he is the three
letters odp
so that's kinda frustrating
but we can take a quick peek at that and
i'll show you a unequal
network this text here
so i did
control space
i'd use the control of the is jumped in
and of line
really anyone
so there's control easy
jumped and
and control okay
his job to begin
if you want a copy of a wine that
certainly
so regular control he
and then i didint
malad w so i copy back
media control acts coz jump over to the
one
and it controlled y
and pasted
within a couple weeks you guys will be
able to speak
syrup you know it's a review come with
some of the country your work on your
anguish
and you're also bargain speaking
he max will be the strangest language
that you know
so free run this command
we're gonna actually count goes out and
see that it's more
so if you run echo without the vcd
it's gonna print out the string
and step i picked this little command
called bc and that's a binary calculator
if you want to selection
yet again
some of you control space at the
beginning of the ako
animus get the control economist for the
graph part of it and she adds
took
uh... so the mark and turn on or off if
you keep doing control space unit toggle
it basically
market activated when you're starting to
now use their piece
and now you can demand a w
and we're gonna keep goin through this
everyday
for pretty much the rest of the semester
such a momentum w
patrol explode sitting on the other side
control ex-wife case just the echo
command
dot takes that tax i built a little
equation i just took the three number
four plus and i passed it to the binary
calculator
then calculate out that some
now we're going to do too much with
these things after today in time
tuesday
after this we're gonna sort of ignored
these guys will say don't do a lot of
python
but it's great to have these
i personally if we are just working with
the attorney figure things out
and you can use them from with insider
the ipod iphone shall we start to use
so if you want to make this better
and we do you arm
weepy
from our whole sorted first example of
that
historical
and scroll through some of us to show
you guys that
the weight is texas' has a column
odp in a common for the note if you want
to go the bottom
come on
i repeat policy you can start looking at
the tax and see if there's if you can
ease alleged information to figure out
how to just get those soap week around
the old one run the old practice for
find yourself we
pace that with a control line
so here i brian the old command with he
crept
odp holes
and we can use those commas to help
ourselves out
we put a comma and a comma
on either side of that odp and if you
could not
aloni one of them
you give her
make these commands chip away
works well for you
i don't need it note i'd just felt like
right now i want to get off slightly
differently because i feel like that
seem both thomas helps me out mentally
figure out what's going on
like every run back
and becomes al a little bit lower and
its remove those are the key
entries in there
the detect history
and then you can use the exclamation
point and uh... command number
so if i want to rerun
the bc one which is three eighteen have
to do bank three eighteen
what you wanted
you're didn't allowed
we had the control that's
for search
there's control are for search back the
other way if thats looking easier
so i can do a control are search
backwards
and i can type
bc
unit has been zack match
and keeping back until i get to work
with control are
and i can go out of this
an infinite number of ways to slice
this'
and so if you ask ben so long as he has
a really great textbook that you awhile
back that is still
right on the money for all the stuff
voyage have slightly different way to do
it
they're both right
i'm not sure how you guys are getting
into the small
uh... c
they killed so they do signals
it will also be to add to that
also refer to that
so wavy max it's using all of these keys
like control c
if you want to do something like that
control see that we use in a terminal
there's a menu item here called signals
and you can send a control see to that
terminal
there's a hockey is control c control
see here
but they had bags liking control c
a separate right on the screen menu bar
signals or a
he controls the control c
it's effectively doing
breaking out of uh... commanded terminal
so if you guys
and up in a mode where nothing's
happening in this e-mail shell
compass signals and select break
what's the mecca plot discussed
early once in a state before we end
today
and also action talking about out
program called the new plot were only
getting used to gnuplot today and then
i'm going to force myself to never touch
again for the rest of class
and upset cases
out where to focus on that plot led from
pipeline after those but i want to show
you these were plotting program
there are
hundreds if not thousands applauding
programs for our products
they all have their tradeoffs
deploy is an old standby
it's just really hard to make it
as customized
functionalized
map obviously icon
what we need to do for this as we need
to take that data
and we need to pull out the latitude
longitude tramp on up
and one check that you can do with maps
as they don't have to be in a new
projection see or hear a lot of our
projections for me and people but
you can just plot coordinate civic duty
and you can just plotting a graph
and it might be
a lot confusing because you don't have
corner frames in scale bars and things
like that on it but he is going to see
what's in there
and see if the date of looks good just
plodding whatever quota numbers happen
to be in there and see what comes out
can be very helpful
and you're gonna see here that world
we're gonna surprise
so please take a quick look at
go ahead and were in iran
attack a minimalist see if we can pull
out the fifth and six columns
for that so
spengler quicksand prep program
recently incorrect program
holes
i pulled out that first line by grabbing
for another work program is only an
that's for table contents line beginning
so expedition is one sites
poles three programs for
wanted to know racks is going to be fine
and lots he's going to be six
so i can use that same
cut command say it
cuts testing
commonwealths what others commas
and we'll grab calms five and six
for holes
csd
lapierre we got lucky and
dot rights to take those we sought lots
of loud caesar
one season latitudes
people tell us a laugh along with a lot
of times
when you work with
computers most don't want x_y_z_ and not
order
and people tend to say lat long soul
there's lots of times reunifying their
swat but not today
starts grades buccaneer plot want
something that's got
not commons
but it actually want spaces between each
of those
so we need to figure out how to
convergys
those commas two spaces and there's a
commands
tiara for translate
and what you do is you get it
the character of the great don't want to
have so we have a comma
and the workplace that with a space
am we can then take our allpolitics
from the cut command
half fit into this for the tight
vertical bar
and then
we can
using it
control thing
where we send to a file
so this is a redirect
and as the greater than symbol
and then
some file
so this will send whatever's going here
it sees this symbol says i'm gonna send
it to a file
and then you get the name of the file he
walked with me
so that way we can actually sable
going on with the senate finance
so if we say
and chemistry one more thing before
they're back to me and
so before we use grep ended
give us matches that first line
with the
program what she wants all that is going
to confuse
the new flight doesn't like having
random text in there
egret has an option called dash v as in
victor
and that's what's not so that it will
throw out any line that matches the
seeds act off that before
grabbed everything that matched odp
variety p
now it's going to say anything that
matches that string
throw that day that way
so we're gonna
for a way that first line
so that will be
this parade here
and if we do u fingerprinting to had how
babble p
so ignore the broken pipe nonsense
coming from rucker
and so if you look here here's the
beginning of the commands believe he
crept minus the
longitude
and in the whole celsius defile
and i first wind disappears recovered
about
so what's now combine that with our cut
so we're going to get rid of firstline
them use the cut
to grab are allowed to go on student
the bernie is that translate the tiara
commands
to switch from a comma
to a space
made w the copy that
and will do
control why yank
amount piped out to head and we'll do
that redirection second to file
so if you look here
thankfully we only got
one little broken pipe for him
so we did a key cryptogram
during the first line
to pull out a lot to longitude
the translate to switch the common to
the space
and then will add that the first time
lines and here we have
longitude and wanted to nice calm for
the spacing
for send that to a file
will call it ex wife dot dat
so for now if you had
x_y_ dot dat
we now have our data
looks pretty good
okay
this is when you get tripped up very
easily because there's a lot of
punctuation running around in your case
you left in the political bar
you've ever nicobar goes away into a
place where
this
serrated here
hit a brick a bar and that than it's
been a
if we each of data
or peter
foods he grew up in
you can look at this time
control you
and don't forget
to replace that vertical bar in head
their now do their career bam
and the ex wife dot that
approaching it's not a whole keith work
pretty well
prisoner
president reagan
going on
sent the signal break
and friends type in the community and
scratches
that's a a good one that wiped out the
file seem to run the command again
you're is something new laptop
so there's a
important point and move
as explain this
later on a possibility won't make it
till tuesday
every time you do this
thus far there's something there
will get destroyed
so every time you do this command
it's going to wipe out anything is there
were four and right right over the top
of it
and do without telling
it's pretty easy to destroy file that
you really want have around
and troubles here
well nan
yet green
ministry
another did feet is up
an uptick in the end of the terminal
yes but you actually you're making a
couple problems one is the key targets
in space after here
and then you have africa borrowing you'd
com
try head of your ex white out that
dispatchers skin
headspace ex-wife about that
awesome let's make a plot
there at this point burns called the new
plot so right in the new plot
and let's fought this data
now here you have to use a single quote
it does not like
double quotes for some reason terry
grumpy
so plot space ex wife dot dot
press enter
and you're going to get a graphic of
global plots
someone tell me what they think cecil
good does this look like it's the right
thing order something weird about this
file
whilst everybody up so they've got a
plot going
for him to enter
and this is uh...
where we were in the field data has
appeal warts uh...
include
sudo apt-get
gnuplot
who have responded
a plot of the day
at the clean up their papa notes plot
space
single quote
and that's why dot that
single quotes preceptor
facing here we go ahead
so this is clearly not
happy dataset
lat long
it's goes from minus twenty eight two
plus one and so on to the phil k the lad
soon
is going up here to lasted a five
thousand something or other
but there's something wrong
they hadn't is is that somebody put that
tassel place wrong point two days
so these files
when they're up here at fifty-six or
fifty seven
thousand actually should be fifty seven
point upset
but what we can do both
we're not going to fix that database yet
will fix it later on
and we'll do a lot more with it
we can
go back to our plot over here
and say set
while range
who's gonna go ahead and give it to you
because
or not to spend more time with this what
was said to me
my desire for signing a moderate or
anything outside of that
plot range
set y range
and then we'll go back up to our plot
for center again
and if you've got a good imagination
you should now be able to see
africa asia
whatnot in all the comments that should
be white-space
plus a lot of white space all over the
globe because
will have three thousand something
course for the whole world which means
that we
missed most of the world
calamity body and yet
or if you scroll up in a manner on that
now if you want to see what's going on
at datafile
we can put out of this
and do member the command from homework
maths
and the kids the ex-wife
thought that
so we can see that
wanted to drainage
minus one seventy nine and something
two seventeen one seven nine something
allotted
the southern hemisphere looks pretty
good minus seventy seven
but we've got that fifties
seven thousand
and what not so we can then
see that the lights he does it make a
lot of sense so this way
really dug in vichu far what we've
that able to identify a class of
problems in our data
that we don't have to fix before we can
take
i'm affable wells
and so right now it's end of the class
for today
we diverted today we jump through a lot
of
the max hoops
if you're new team at century your brain
is probably overloaded
where they go through it and
just keep asking that's the best way
doing that when you get stock
as ask
i will also put in the uh...
class notes for today o link ralph hope
rebuild them tonight or tomorrow and
open the link to a cheat sheet you can
print out that if you make a double site
is one piece of paper
and it has several hundred of these keys
on it
they're probably be
eighty percent of the nephew asking what
they do i don't know
they'll be some funky he max thing that
i've never tried
but the basics for the industry
so that she she has got some really
great commands
uh... and a lot more time
because i don't know
me five percent inexorably
awfully generous help
great job on all the questions
opportunities
which was uh... t
what every time you had something it's
coming in there yet
yet but one travelers bring down we were
doing is it's not going anywhere else
so you're not going to say that
smokeless phil gramm
pre-war apartments apartment rockbox
member also that for with prashant
show that they don't really want to be
like which come in here and that
said violence is that the tower trend
arround the old one
so you know who they are in command
so if you have
arround
homework doing
bring placements
dot for
these into
if you make any part
and he's trying to compress it it's
going to complain forces already here
so do you
the or income
and then that are the weakness for and
and
action
it's a learning experience so
getting it wrong is actually ok right
now
really want you to you
the process of getting it
towards right because what mattered